( BUZZING )
CANDYMAN : They will say that I have shed innocent blood .
What 's blood for , if not for shedding ?
With my hook for a hand ,
I 'll sp / it you from your groin
to your gullet .
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
CAN DYMAN : I came for you .
GIRL : It 's the scariest story I have ever heard , and it 's totally true .
It happened a few years ago , near Moses Lake , in Indiana .
Clara was babysitting for the Johnsons ,
and Billy pulls up on his motorcycle .
Now , she wasn 't even going out with Bil / y .
She was actually going out with Michael for about six months .
But she always had the hots for Billy
'cause he was like a bad boy .
And Michael was just so nice .
So , anyway , she decides that tonight 's the night
that she 's gonna give Billy what she never gave to Michael .
Have you ever heard of Candyman ?
No .
Well , his right hand is sawn off
and he has a hook jammed in the bloody stump .
And if you look in the mirror ,
and you say his name five times ,
he 'll appear behind you breathing down your neck .
You wanna try it ?
GIRL : So Billy began .
He looked in the mirror and he said ...
Candyman .
No one ever got past four .
Not here .
Go downstairs .
I have a surprise for you .
( CHUCKLES )
GIRL : She looked in the mirror ,
and I don 't know why ,
but she said his name the last time .
Candyman .
She turned out the lights ...
( CLARA SCREAMING )
What he saw turned his hair white from shock .
Killed her ,
split her open with his hook , and then killed the baby , too .
And Billy got away ,
but soon after he went crazy .
My roommate 's boyfriend knows him .
So , when did you first hear this story ?
My friend heard it on the radio . It 's true . Sick , huh ?
The babysitter just roasted the kid ,
like it was a turkey or something .
So , what 's the deal ?
You guys doing a page on serial killers or something ?
Something like that .
Well , that 's it . We 're done .
All right . Thanks .
No problem .
See ya . See ya .
See ya . ( BOTH GIGGLE )
Seems like they 're gettin younger every day .
TREVOR : Does anybody remember the craze for the pet baby alligators ?
DIANE : When they got too large to keep ,
people flushed them down the toilet .
They live in the sewers now .
Some of them are 30-feet long .
TREVOR : Where did this happen ?
DIAN E : Ln Miami .
They went blind and albino from living in the dark .
( STUDENTS LAUGHING )
DANNY : Sir , it wasn 't Miami , it was New York .
I read it in the paper .
Oh , well , then it must be true .
( ALL LAUGHING )
Why would Danny and Diane both be suffering from the same delusion ,
in two cities , over 1,000 miles apart ?
Let 's face it , folks .
There are no alligators in the sewers .
No , it 's round the campfire , it 's bedtime stories .
See , these stories are modern , oral folklore .
They are the unselfconscious reflection of the fears of urban society .
( BELL RINGING )
Thafslunch .
The primordial reptile is then transformed into this monster , right ? Why ?
Ah , the dashing professor .
The lovely wife .
Hello .
Helen , you know everybody ?
The créme de la créme . Harold .
Hi .
Diane , Daniel , Stacey .
Hi . Hello .
So , keep up the good work .
Thank you for the contributions .
Thanks . Bye . Awesome lecture .
See you .
Bye .
See ya .
So you wanna tell me about this girl ?
What 's her name ? Stacey .
She could barely look me in the eyes , Trevor ,
and I swear she was blushing .
Well , I guess that 's because she 's madly in love with me .
You know , all those bursting adolescent hormones .
You don 't really think ...
No , of course not .
Good . I should hope not . So , what 's the matter ?
Trevor ,
you promised you wouldn 't do
the urban legends lecture until next semester .
You knew that Bernadette and I were gathering data from the freshmen ,
so why did you have to ruin it ? ( SIGHS )
Honey , you 're my wife and I love you dearly ,
but you can 't expect me to hold up their education
while the two of you complete your thesis . I mean , be realistic .
I have a curriculum I have to follow here .
Yes , I know .
Well ? So don 't be mad at me .
GIRL ON TAPE : / fyou look in the mirror
and say his name five times ,
he ' / / appear behind you breathing down your neck .
( KEYS CLATTERING )
Can I clean the room ?
Oh , sure . Don 't mind me .
GIRL ON TAPE : So Billy began .
He looked in the mirror and he said ...
" Candyman , Candyman , Candyman ... "
Candyman , huh ?
Yes , have you heard of him ?
Mmm-hmm . You doing a study on him ?
Yes , I am . What have you heard ?
Everybody 's scared of him once it get dark .
He live over at Cabrini . My friend told me about him .
Cabrini-Green ?
Yeah , in the projects .
I live on the South Side , so I don 't know too much about it ,
but my friend , she know all about it .
Her cousin live at Cabrini .
They say he killed a lady .
Can I talk to your friend ?
Sure .
Kitty ?
Yeah ? What do you want ?
Lady down here wanna talk to you .
All right .
She coming ' .
I 'm Helen Lyle .
Pleased to meet you . Henrietta Mosely .
And this is Kitty Culver .
Hello .
Tell her what you told me about the Candyman .
All I know was there was some lady in a tub , and she heard a noise .
Do you remember her name ?
I think her name was Ruthie Jean .
And she heard this banging and smashing ,
like somebody was tryin to make a hole in the wall .
So Ruthie called 911 and she said ,
" There 's somebody comin through the walls . "
And they didn 't believe her .
They thought the lady was crazy , right ?
Mmm-hmm .
So she called 911 again , and they still didn 't believe her .
But when they finally got there , she was dead .
Was she shot ?
No .
She was killed with a hook .
( MIMICS SLICING )
HENRIETTA : It 's true .
Yeah , it is . I read it in the papers .
Candyman killed her .
Yeah , but I don 't know nothin ' about that .
BERNADETTE : Helen , this is sick .
This isn 't one of your fairytales . A woman got killed here .
Jesus .
That 's not the half of it .
Now , that 's Cabrini-Green ,
not that you 'd recognize it today .
Yeah , no kidding . I won 't even drive past there .
Heard a kid got shot there the other day .
Every day .
Okay , now look carefully at this picture .
And then this one .
You spot it ?
No .
That 's not Cabrini-Green .
That 's this building , Lincoln Village .
My apartment was built as a housing project .
No . Yeah .
Now take a look at this .
Once it was finished , the city soon realized
that there was no barrier between here and the Gold Coast .
Unlike over there , where you got the highway
and the " L " train to keep the ghetto cut off .
Exactly . So they made some minor alterations .
They covered the cinder block in plaster
and they sold the lot off as condos .
How much did you pay for this place ?
Don 't ask . ( LAUGHS )
Now wait till you see this .
Here 's the proof .
The killer , or killers , they don 't know which ,
smashed their way through the back of this cabinet .
See , there 's no wall there .
It 's only a medicine chest separating us from the other apartment .
Hey , hey , wait ! What are you doing ?
There could be somebody on the toilet .
No , the apartment 's vacant . Are you sure ?
Yes .
There .
Okay . Now take a look .
BERNADETTE : That is amazing .
( GASPS )
What ? There 's somebody in there .
I saw a light go on .
There 's nobody there .
Psych .
That 's not funny . That was not funny .
( LAUGHING )
You didn 't scare me at all .
Yeah , right .
Ow .
You don 't believe all that nonsense anyway , do you ?
I don 't . Do you ?
No .
All right .
BOTH : Candyman , Candyman ,
Candyman , Candyman ,
Candyman .
Oh , you chicken ! ( LAUGHS )
You have to do it five times . Go on . Go again .
BERNADETTE : I 'm sorry ...
HELEN : I did it ...
( CLOCK TICKING )
( SOFT THUD )
Trevor ?
( SCREAMING )
Oh , Trevor !
What ? Who were you expecting ?
( SIGHS )
What time is it ?
It 's late , and I 'm smashed .
Sorry I scared you .
What 's with the arsenal , Bernadette ?
We 're only going eight blocks .
You 're the one who got us dressed up like cops .
I just said dress conservatively .
Yeah , well , we look like cops .
Why are you trying to scare me ?
I 'm not trying to scare you , Helen .
I just want you to think , okay ?
The gangs hold this whole neighborhood hostage .
Okay , let 's just turn around then ! Let 's just go back ,
and we can write a nice little boring thesis ,
regurgitating all the usual crap about urban legend .
We 've got a real shot here , Bernadette .
An entire community starts attributing the daily horrors of their lives
to a mythical figure .
Now , if Trevor and Archie were in on this ,
do you think they 'd chicken out ?
In a second .
Exactly .
( SIGHING ) All right .
Yo , G , what 's up ? What 's up , man ?
You wanna wait here for me ?
No .
Well , then let 's go .
Check them out .
HELEN : And lock the car .
MAN 1 : Hey , now . Whoo !
Want something ' , baby ?
I got it for you .
MAN 2 : Say , yo , mama . Come over here , baby . Come on , come on .
Yo , baby .
Which way you goin ' ?
Just going inside .
Yeah ? ( MAN LAUGHING )
MAN 1 : Y 'all can 't come up in here . MAN 2 : Can 't come up in here .
Excuse me , y 'all can 't come up in here .
Who you lookin ' for ?
Just going up to see a friend of ours .
Sure you 're not the police , huh ?
MAN 3 : Look like Five-O to me .
Ask blondie where she goin ' .
Who she goin ' to see ?
Who you goin ' to see ?
Let 's take the stairs . Come on .
Where you all goin ' there ?
( WHISTLING )
Heads up , people ! Five-O comin up the back door ! Police !
It 's okay . They think we 're cops .
They 're not going to follow us .
Hang on .
Look at this .
Oh , this is great .
( CAMERA CLICKING )
BERNADETTE : " Sweets to ... "
HELEN : " The sweet . "
" Sweets to the sweet . "
Hurry up , Helen .
Let me just get the door .
( BARKING )
Sorry .
Jesus , Helen .
Here it is .
Don 't go in there .
Come on , come on .
Jesus , it stinks .
See , I was right . The layout is identical .
Which means that the bathroom is over there .
Helen ...
What 's the problem ?
A woman died in there . Leaveit .
It 's all right . There 's nothing to see .
( CAMERA CLICKING )
God .
Wait a minute .
This is where he crawled through , right ?
Yeah .
Well , we found it . Let 's go .
Wait a second .
Okay . Hang onto this .
What ?
I 'm just gonna go through ,
and when I get back , we 're out of here .
You gotta be kidding .
Oh , come on . It 's just a derelict apartment .
What if somebody 's packing drugs in there ?
You 're just gonna apologize and give them your card ?
Huh ?
All right . Let 's listen .
HELEN : There 's nobody in there .
Okay .
But hurry up . Be careful .
Give me the camera .
You got five minutes .
Okay . Five .
( CAMERA CLICKING )
( CAMERA WHIRRING )
Damn it .
( SIGHS )
Bernadette ! Sorry . ( GASPS )
Iran out of film . I 've gotta go back .
No way . You can 't believe what ...
No way , Helen . We 're out of here .
( DOG BARKS )
Hey , what y 'all doin ' in there ?
We 're just leaving .
You here for the sweet ?
HELEN : No .
We 're not cops .
We 're from the university .
Well , you don 't belong here , lady .
You don 't belong goin ' through people 's apartments and things .
My name is Helen Lyle and this is Bernadette Walsh .
We 're doing a thesis ,
and we were wondering if we could just talk to you for a few minutes .
Here . This is my card .
( BABY CRYING )
My baby . Come on .
Come on . Let 's go . Come on .
You know , whites don 't ever come here ,
except to cause us a problem .
Believe me , that 's not what we want to do .
( SOFTLY ) Let 's go .
So you say you 're doing a study ?
What you gonna say ?
That we 're bad ? Hmm ?
We steal ? We gangbang ?
We all on drugs , right ?
We ain 't all like them assholes downstairs , you know .
I just wanna raise my child good .
He 's a beautiful little boy .
He 's all I got .
What 's his name ?
Anthony .
I 'm Anne-Marie .
Anne-Marie McCoy .
Nice to meet you .
I 'm sorry we disturbed you .
We 'll just get out of your way .
It 's okay .
I don 't mean to be rude . It 's ...
The white folks that come round here
ain 't too handshakin' with us , you know ?
( BABY GURGLES )
Hey , what you doin ' ? HELEN : Let me help you .
Oh .
Making a mess here , huh ?
Thank you . Thanks .
You got kids ?
No , but I 'd love one . Hey .
Got my eye on this one , big time .
Yeah . They 're not gonna get him .
You wanna know about Ruthie Jean ?
They all been here , you know .
Newspapers , cops , case workers .
They all wanna know .
I heard her screamin ' .
I heard her right through the walls .
I dialed 911 . Nobody came .
Nobody came .
Everybody scared .
He can come right through these walls , you know ?
I 'm scared .
Scared for my child .
They ain 't never gonna catch him .
Who ?
Candyman .
( PURCELL LAUGHING )
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
If they saw something they liked , they 'd point .
They thought it was rude to point .
What did they do ? They went ... ( GRUNTS )
Spat over people . It 's quite extraordinary .
Be nice . I am being nice .
I 'm being very nice .
So how are the two most beautiful
graduate students getting along , then ?
Trevor tells me you 've been dabbling in my favorite subject .
Well , I can 't wait to review your data .
I think I can fit you in tomorrow morning .
We 're not ready yet .
That 's precisely the moment at which I can be of greatest assistance .
Before you disappear down a path to academic Bolivia .
( BOTH LAUGHING )
TREVOR : I think I 've been there . ( PURCELL LAUGHING )
Actually , Purcell , we 're about to bury you .
Helen ... What ?
( MOUTHING )
I 'm sure we 're gonna have something for you in a week or so .
It 's just that we only went to Cabrini today ...
PURCELL : Ah !
Cabrini-Green .
Candyman country .
Well , if you 're after the hook man , Helen ,
you really must read the paper I wrote about him 10 years ago .
You do know the story , don 't you ?
No .
( LAUGHING POMPOUSLY )
Then how are you going to bury me ?
The legend first appeared in 1890 .
Candyman was the son of a slave .
His father had amassed a considerable fortune
from designing a device for the mass-producing of shoes
after the Civil War .
Candyman had been sent to all the best schools ,
and had grown up in polite society .
He had a prodigious talent as an artist
and was much sought after
when it came to the documenting of one 's wealth and position
in society , in a portrait .
It was in this latter capacity
that he was commissioned by a wealthy landowner
to Capture his daughter 's virginal beauty .
Well , of course , they fell deeply in love ,
and she became pregnant .
( SCOFFS )
Poor Candyman .
The father executed a terrible revenge .
He paid a pack of brutal hooligans to do the deed .
They chased Candyman through the town to Cabrini-Green ,
where they proceeded to saw off his right hand with a rusty blade .
( SAWING ) ( MAN SCREAMING )
And no one came to his aid .
But this was just the beginning of his ordeal .
Nearby , there was an apiary .
Dozens of hives filled with hungry bees .
( SCREAMING CONTINUES )
They smashed the hives and stole the honeycomb ,
and smeared it over his prone , naked body .
Candyman was stung to death by the bees .
They burned his body on a giant pyre
and then scattered his ashes over Cabrini-Green .
Hello .
Anne-Marie ain 't in .
Are you sure ?
Yeah . She said you 'd be back .
( BARKING )
What 's your name ?
Jake .
Well , listen , Jake , maybe you can help me out .
I wanted to find out about that woman who got killed .
Do you know anything about that ?
Her name was Ruthie Jean .
I don 't know nothin ' .
Did anybody else talk about it ?
You know , it 's okay to talk to me , Jake ,
'cause I 'm not a cop .
So nobody 's gonna get in trouble .
I can 't say nothin ' , or Candyman 'II get me .
Candyman , huh ?
You scared of him ?
I ain 't scared of nobody .
But you 're crazy walkin ' here on your own .
It ain 't safe around here .
Yeah , I know .
But I don 't scare too easy either , Jake .
You know , you don 't have to tell me .
You could just show me .
And if you show me where Candyman is , I 'll make you a promise .
It 'll be our secret .
Unless you 're too scared .
Somebody building a bonfire ?
Yeah , for the party .
In there .
Candyman 's in there ?
My friend Charlie says so .
A boy got killed there .
Who was he ?
Ain 't sure .
Charlie tell me he was weird .
He was crazy ?
No , a retard .
( CAMERA CLICKING )
His mom was in the store .
And the boy needed to go to the bathroom .
His mom was takin ' her time ,
choosing ' this , lookin ' at that .
So the boy started moaning ' . His mom get mad at him .
Sent him across the street .
His mom was at the Checkout .
She hears her boy screaming ' .
BOY : ( SCREAMING ) Mommy !
Mommy !
There 's a big tough guy .
He runs over to check it out .
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
JAKE : Come out of there shakin ' and cryin ' .
He only been in there five seconds .
Come out of there and his hair turned white .
I mean , it turned white , just like that .
Was the boy murdered ?
Worse .
He 's lying on the floor in a pool of blood , holdin ' himself .
( BOY SCREAMING )
Mommy !
They found it floating in a toilet .
Can 't fix that . Better off dead .
Did Candyman do this ?
Listen , you wait here for me , okay ?
Okay .
( CAMERA CLICKING )
Hello ?
( GASPS )
( COUGHING )
( BUZZING ) ( HELEN EXCLAIMS )
Candyman .
Oh , excuse me .
I 'm done here . I 'll just get out of your way .
Listen , I don 't want to interfere with your business .
I 'm not a cop .
I 'm from the University of Illinois .
I 'll just get out of your way .
Hey , come on ! Let me go !
Look , you 're not being very smart .
My colleagues know where I am and they 're expecting me back .
Now let me go !
Ihear you 're lookin for Candyman , bitch .
Well , you found him .
We hear you 're looking for Candyman , bitch .
VALENTO : Step back .
Number four , step forward and say the line .
We hear you 're looking for Candyman , bitch .
VALENTO : Step back .
Number five , step forward and say the line .
We hear you 're looking for Candyman , bitch .
VALENTO : Step back . Take them out .
He 's number five .
Good work .
( SIGHS )
How 'd you catch him ?
We swept the place .
We start from the top floor and work our way down .
That way you can flush them all out .
Whole of Cabrini 's locked down now .
You 're very lucky to be alive , Ms. Lyle .
Did he kill Ruthie Jean ?
No question .
Killed that poor kid as well .
He ran the Overlords .
Oh , we knew everything about him .
Only reason why we didn 't bring him in before
because we couldn 't find anyone to testify .
We can 't protect them down at Cabrini-Green , and they knew that .
What about the little boy , Jake ?
We don 't need him . We have you .
Hey , Jake .
Listen , I just wanted to thank you for saving my life .
I wanna go home .
We 'll get you out of here right away , kid .
You did good .
You said it was our secret .
You lied .
It still is , Jake .
You won 't have to go to court .
( WHISPERS ) Candyman will get me .
Candyman isn 't real .
He 's just a story .
You know , like Dracula or Frankenstein .
A bad man took his name so he could scare us .
But now that he 's locked up , everything 's gonna be okay .
Candyman ain 't real ?
No .
( DOOR UNLOCKING )
Hey !
Slow down !
You 're supposed to be the invalid here .
No , it 's much better . Look . See ? It 's much better today .
Yeah , it looks great .
Come sit down .
( CHUCKLES )
You haven 't eaten already , have you ?
No , of course not .
Okay , good .
BERNADETTE : Hey ,
welcome back .
Thanks . Let me see .
I 'm so glad you 're okay . I would 've totally freaked .
Yeah , but you know what bugs me about the whole thing ?
Two people get brutally murdered and the cops do nothing .
Whereas a white woman goes in there and gets attacked ,
and they lock the place down . Yeah , I know ,
but this was a bad guy . You got him put away .
That 's all that matters .
Oh ! I 've got a surprise for you .
What ?
You 're not gonna believe it .
The pictures . A friend of mine
in the photography department managed to save most of them .
I 'd written them off . The camera was smashed .
That 's not all .
I 've been talking to some publishers ,
and there 's a lot of interest since you made the local section .
We 're gonna be published .
All right . So I 'll come over tomorrow at 9 : 00 , and we 'll get started , right ?
Yeah . Okay .
( HORN HONKING )
CANDYMAN : Helen .
Yes ?
Who is that ?
Helen .
I came for you .
Do I know you ?
No .
No , but you doubted me .
I 'm sorry . I have to go .
No need to leave yet .
But I 'm late .
You are not content with the stories ,
so I was obliged to come .
( SIGHS )
Be my victim .
I am the writing on the wall ,
the whisper in the classroom .
Without these things , I am nothing .
So now , I must shed innocent blood .
Come with me .
( ANNE-MARIE SCREAMING )
( ANNE-MARIE MOANING )
( ANNIE-MARIE SOBBING )
ANNE-MARIE : No !
( ANNE-MARIE SCREAMING )
( SOBBING )
Anthony !
No , no ! No ! No !
( CONTINUES SOBBING )
Anthony !
Anne-Marie ?
( YELLING ) No ! You bitch ! You bitch !
Stay back ! Stay back ! Where 's my baby ?
Where 's my baby ? No !
My baby !
You murderer !
You ... No !
Stop ! Please , stop ! Stop .
( SCREAMING )
Now , stop ! Stop !
Police ! Open up !
All right , hold it right there !
Back away ! Now !
( SCREAMING )
Look out , look out !
( HELICOPTER HOVERING )
Remove your sweater .
( SOBBING )
Drop it and slide it over to me .
Take off your brassiere .
Can I please take a shower ?
( GROANS )
Oh , God .
Drop it , slide it over to me .
Lift up your arms .
Lift your left breast .
Your right .
Remove your underwear .
Can I please speak with Detective Valento ?
Frank .
Ms. Lyle , you 're under arrest .
Do you understand ?
Please let me explain .
Yes , but ...
You have the right to remain silent .
Do you understand ?
This is crazy . I was attacked .
Respond to the question !
I understand .
At approximately 10 : 00 p.m. ,
Anne-Marie McCoy returned to her apartment .
She discovered her dog with its head cut off .
She cried for assistance ,
at which point you attacked her with a meat cleaver .
You were still in possession of this weapon
when the arresting officers came to her aid .
DETECTIVE : Where 's the baby ?
I don 't know .
You 're sick .
VALENTO : Before I ask any further questions ,
would you like to have counsel ?
( BANGS TABLE ) Yes or no ?
( STUTTERING ) I would like to make a phone call .
( RINGING )
( ANSWERING MACHINE CLICKS )
TREVOR : I 'm sorry , we can 't take your call .
Please leave a message after the tone .
Trevor , are you there ? Pick up .
It 's an emergency , Trevor . Pick up the phone !
I 've been arrested . I 'm at the 18th District .
Can you please come pick me up ?
That 's it .
Do you know what time it is ?
3 : 00 a.m.
( DOOR SLAMMING ) ( KEYS JINGLING )
( BABY COOING )
( ANNE-MARIE WAILING )
( DOOR OPENS )
Oh , God .
( CROWD CLAMORING )
There 's gotta be another way out of here .
ATTORNEY : Cover her face . Don 't say anything .
Just have to walk to the car .
TREVOR : Okay ? That 's it .
All right . Here we go .
You 'll be fine . Stick with me .
REPORTER : There she is ! There she is !
Just keep your head down .
( ALL CLAMORING )
All right , people . Back off . Back off . We have no comment .
Absolutely no comment . Nothing to say .
We have absolutely nothing to say ! No comment !
My client has not been charged with a thing !
FEMALE REPORTER ON TV : Some information has indicated
that baby Anthony was abducted and may still be alive .
The blood may have come from the dog .
A suspect was released this morning after questioning ,
and I guess we 'll just have to follow this one as it ...
Well , at least they didn 't mention your name . That 's good .
Now , they haven 't charged you
because they think they 'll find the body .
Which means , I 'm afraid , they 're shooting for murder one ,
but I don 't think they have a chance .
Do you think I did it ?
No , nobody believes that .
But it 's crossed your mind ?
ATTORNEY : Is there anything ,
any detail , however small ,
that you can recall that would help us
substantiate your version of events ?
I blacked out .
I don 't know what happened .
I just woke up in that place
and there was blood everywhere .
Can I get you anything ?
Are you sure ?
Look , honey , I was supposed to go over to the campus
and pick up some work .
I 'm concerned about leaving you alone , though .
I 'll only be about 20 minutes . Trevor ?
Where were you last night ?
I was here . I was fast asleep .
I thought you were with Bernadette .
Look , honey , I 'm gonna stand by you .
We 're gonna get through this , okay ?
I 'll be right back .
( DOOR OPENS )
( DOOR CLOSES )
( SCREAMS )
Believe in me .
Be my victim .
Come on .
Please .
Do you believe in me ?
Keep away from me !
I have the child .
Allow me to take you , or he will die in your place .
No !
Your disbelief destroyed the faith of my congregation .
Without them , I am nothing .
So I was obliged to come .
And now I must kill you .
Your death will be a tale to frighten children ,
to make lovers cling closer in their rapture .
Come with me and be immortal .
( GROANING )
Helen ?
Bernadette .
Bernadette , go .
Helen ?
Helen , honey , it 's ...
He 's here .
Bernadette .
Go !
Helen !
Helen ?
Go on ! Get out !
Oh !
( SOBBING ) Oh , no , no , no .
( SLASHING ) ( BERNADETTE SCREAMING )
( CAN DYMAN GRUNTING )
( SLASHING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Trevor ...
Trevor , he 's here .
He 's here . He 's here .
Don 't let him kill me .
Trevor ?
Trevor !
( GRUNTING )
Trevor . Trevor !
Hey , hey . Trevor !
( GROANS )
Take her outside .
Trevor .
Hold me , Trevor , please ?
( BUZZING )
( POLICE RADIO CHATTERING )
CAN DYMAN : Why do you want to live ?
If you would learn just a little from me ,
you would not beg to live .
I am rumor .
/ tis a blessed condition , believe me .
To be whispered about at street corners .
To live in other people ' s dreams , but not to have to be .
Do you understand ?
( BABY CRYING )
HELEN : Please , God , don 't let him kill the baby .
Trevor !
Trevor ?
Where are you going ?
No , you can 't leave me here !
I can 't defend myself !
( GRUNTING )
No .
What do the good know ,
except what the bad teach them by their excesses .
Murderer .
Allow me at least a kiss .
Just one exquisite kiss .
( CRYING )
Murderer !
Help !
Listen , he 's under the bed !
Bring me 1,000 mills .
Listen . He 's here . He 's under the bed !
No . dont
( BABY COOING )
( DOOR OPENS )
( HELEN COUGHING )
She 's coming around . Morning .
I 'd like to speak to my husband .
( CHUCKLES )
So would I.
There we go . What time is it ?
Where are we going ?
We 're going to Disneyland .
( WOMAN ANNOUNCING OVER PA )
Clyde , open it up .
Winley ? Clyde , open it up .
( DOOR BUZZING OPEN )
What the hell are you all doing back there , huh ?
A little reading ? Huh ?
MAN : Freak .
Dr. Burke ? DR. BURKE : Yes .
Ms. Lyle , I 'm Dr. Burke .
I 'd like to speak to my husband .
I 'm sure we can arrange a visit .
A visit ?
Have I been committed ?
Do you really think these restraints are necessary ?
Helen ,
this is a writ of detention from the state attorney 's office .
Now , for the past month ... Month ?
Yes .
We 've been stabilizing you on a heavy dosage of Thorazine .
You probably remember very little , or nothing .
Get me my attorney .
I 'm working for your defense .
We have to assess your ability to stand trial .
Helen ,
you 've been charged with first-degree murder .
Why don 't you tell me what happened in your apartment ?
( HELEN GRUNTING )
The night you were admitted ,
did the killer appear to you ?
Murderer ! Murderer !
Murderer ! Help me !
( GRUNTING )
He 's here ! He 's under the bed !
I don 't understand .
Help ! Please ! He 's here !
Help me ! Help me ! Please !
He 's under the bed . He 's under the bed ...
That 's not possible .
MAN : Bring me 1,000 mil / s .
Bernadette .
( SNIFFLING )
I 'm not capable of that .
No matter what 's going wrong ,
I know one thing . That no part of me ,
no matter how hidden ,
is capable of that .
I can prove it .
H ow ?
I can call him .
Candyman , Candyman ,
Candyman .
( GRUNTS )
( EXCLAIMS )
( CAN DYMAN GRUNTING )
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTING )
You 're mine now .
Tonight our congregation shall witness a new miracle .
( GRUNTS )
( ALARM RINGING )
NURSE : Dr. Burke ?
( BANGING ON DOOR )
Dr. Burke !
Dr. Burke , please answer .
( GROANS )
WOMAN ON PA : Code nine , Ward B-5 , stat .
Code nine , Ward B-5 , stat .
MAN : Check the west wing !
All clear ! Right !
Let 's go ! Go , go !
We have a direction on this one ?
HELEN : Please be home , Trevor . Please be home .
( PANTING )
Get out of my home .
( WHIMPERING ) Trevor !
TREVOR : What 's the matter , sweetie pie ?
Did you make another little boo-boo ?
What are you doing here ?
I live here . Remember ?
Call the hospital .
Don 't touch the phone .
What 's the matter , Trevor ?
Scared of something ?
( SCOFFS )
I hate the color scheme .
What were you gonna do , Trevor ?
Wait till I got out before you told me ?
Helen .
You knew I was never coming out , didn 't you ?
I think we should call the hospital .
Okay .
( DIAL TONE )
Go on .
Is that what you wanna do ?
( SOBBING )
Call them .
( SOFTLY ) I 'm not a murderer .
I 'm not ...
Trevor , you were all Ihadleñ .
( BLEEPING )
It 's over .
RECORDED VOICE : If you 'd like to make a call , please hang up and try again .
CAN DYMAN : They will all abandon you .
All you have left is my desire for you .
( PEOPLE SHOUTING )
( PEOPLE CHATTERING )
( HEAVY BREATHING )
( EXCLAIMS )
Helen .
You came to me .
The Child ...
We had a deal .
Surrender to me now ,
and he shall be unharmed .
We have a bargain .
And I 'm afraid .
Do you fear the pain , or what is beyond ?
Both .
The pain , I can assure you , will be exquisite .
As for our deaths , there is nothing to fear .
Our names will be written on a thousand walls ,
our crimes told and retold by our faithful believers .
We shall die together in front of their very eyes
and give them something to be haunted by .
Come with me
and be immortal .
( EXCLAIMS ) ( BUZZING )
( SCREAMS )
No !
( SCRUNCHING )
( CANDYMAN SHUSHING )
You 're mine now .
It 's time for a new miracle .
( EXCLAIMING )
( PANTING )
CAN DYMAN : Lt was always you , Helen .
It was always you .
( BABY CRYING )
( CRYING CONTINUES )
He 's here .
( CRYING )
HELEN : I 'm coming .
( GRUNTING )
It 's okay .
BOY : Check it out , man .
Yes .
MAN 1 : What happened ?
MAN 2 : They got Candyman out there !
JAKE : Candyman 's in there ! I saw him go in there ! I saw his hook !
The Candyman 's in there ! I saw his hook !
( SHUSHING ) ( CRYING )
I knew you 'd come .
Burn him .
( CHEERING )
( MUFFLED YELL )
Hush .
ALL : ( CHANTING ) Burn him ! Burn him !
Burn him ! Burn him ! Burn him ! Burn him !
Help ! Help !
Help ! Help me !
You lied to me !
CANDYMAN : We must be on our way now , you and I.
Our bones will soon be ashes ,
and we shall never be separated again .
HELEN : Let me go .
Icannot We are already dead .
( CRYING )
( SCREAMING )
Come back to me !
Come back !
( CRYING )
( SCREAMING )
PRIEST : We commend to Almighty God , our sister , Helen ,
and we commit her body to the ground .
Earth to earth , ashes to ashes , dust to dust .
The Lord bless her and keep her and give her peace .
God of holiness and power ,
accept our prayers , on behalf of your servant , Helen .
Do not count her deeds against her ,
for in her heart she desired to do your will .
May Almighty God bless you , the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit .
MAN : My God . Look at that .
PURCELL : Trevor ?
STACEY : Trevor ?
What is it ?
Trevor , are you all right ?
Yeah , I 'm fine .
Aren 't you hungry ?
No , I 'm okay . I 'll eat a little bit later .
I was gonna make us a nice dinner .
Okay . Whatever .
( SIGHS )
Hey , why don 't you help me make the salad ?
Okay . I 'll be there in a minute .
( EXHALES )
( SOBBING )
Helen .
Oh , Helen .
Ow .
What 's the matter , Trevor ?
Scared of something ?
( GROANING )
( GURGUNG )
Trevor ?
My God , Trevor ?
( SCREAMING )